<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>News</title>
<link>http://www.bbc.com</link>
<description>
News from all over the world.
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 1 March 2015 14:20:24 GMT</pubDate>
<image>
    <url>http://www.bbc.com/logo.gif</url>
   <link>http://www.bbc.com/index.php</link>
</image>
<item>
<title>News from Asia</title>
<link>http://www.bbc.com/news/asia/</link>
<description>
Narendra Modi has urged Sri Lanka and India to act like good neighbours, during the first official visit to Colombo by an Indian PM for 28 years.
He promised that his neighbours would benefit from India's status as "the new frontier of economic opportunity".
Analysts say Mr Modi is attempting to counter the increasing influence of China on its island neighbour.
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 2 March 2015 14:20:24 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>News from Australia</title>
<link>http://www.bbc.com/news/australia/</link>
<description>
Swedish prosecutors have offered to travel to London to question Wikileaks founder Julian Assange over sex assault allegations.

Prosecutors had previously insisted on questioning Mr Assange in Sweden, after seeking his arrest in 2010.

Mr Assange denies the assault claims and has been living at the Ecuadorean embassy in London since 2012.

He fears that if he is sent to Sweden he could then be extradited to the US to face charges over leaking material.
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 2 March 2015 14:20:24 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>
News from Health
</title>
<link>http://www.bbc.com/news/health/</link>
<description>
More than 10,000 people have died in the largest ever outbreak of the virus.
But a study in the journal Science suggests there could be even more deaths from other diseases because of the devastating impact on the countries' vaccination programmes.
Experts said an increase in such infections was "likely".
There have been 24,350 cases of Ebola in Liberia, Guinea and Sierra Leone.
Many healthcare facilities closed and the fear of Ebola meant people did not show up at those that remained.
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 2 March 2015 14:20:24 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>News from Science/Environment</title>
<link>http://www.bbc.com/news/science/</link>
<description>
An initiative has been launched to help improve smallholder farmers' access to a wider array of modern, more productive food crop varieties.
The African Seed Access Index (TASAI) monitors the state of the continent's seed sector and highlights problems that prevent seeds reaching farmers.
Organisers hope the scheme will shake off "decades of complacent government seed monopolies".
Uganda, Zimbabwe, South Africa and Kenya featured in the first assessment.</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 2 March 2015 14:20:24 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
<title>News from Technology</title>
<link>http://www.bbc.com/news/technology/</link>
<description>
Destiny has been named as best game at 2015's British Academy Game Awards.
The post-apocalyptic first-person shooter was developed by Bungie. It was the US studio's first release after quitting the Halo series.
The title attracted mixed reviews, and its relatively bare-bones plot continues to divide gamers.
The award surprised many in the audience at the London ceremony as it had not won any of the other categories it had been nominated for.
However, Bungie's skill at crafting alien-slaying gunfights appears to have helped it seize the top prize.
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 2 March 2015 14:20:24 GMT</pubDate>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>