<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <generator>RSS Builder by B!Soft</generator>
    <title>LocalBanya home page</title>
    <link>file:///E:/sukhada/index.html</link>
    <description>Online Grossary store</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <webMaster>sukhada.khatu@gmail.com</webMaster>
    <copyright>ssrry</copyright>
    <item>
      <title>Riya's Grilled Plums with Orange Yogurt &amp; Pistachios</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 9 Mar 2015 22:45:37 +0500</pubDate>
      <category>Recipes</category>
      <description><![CDATA[Very interesting one here for you from her kitchen! Make these soon and tell us all about how they turned out!
Grilled Plums with orange yogurt and pistachios 

Ingredients:

For the grilled plums:

4 plums, cut into halves and pitted 

1 tsp of honey 

½ tsp of orange zest 

A pinch of cinnamon powder 

½ tsp of oil (I used sunflower) 

Method:

Place the plums cut side up on a plate on in a bowl. Sprinkle the orange zest, cinnamon powder and honey over this. 

Allow it to rest for five minutes. 

Heat a pan on medium heat. Drizzle the oil over this and when the pan becomes very hot, gently place the plums on it, cut side down. 

Let the plums cook for about 4-5 minutes, which will also make sure the caramelization process kicks into action. 

Once they’re done, remove from the pan and put them on the plate or bowl you want to serve them in. 

Inrgedients:

For the orange yogurt:

1 cup of thick yogurt

1 tsp of orange zest 

1 tsp of honey 

A pinch of cinnamon powder 

Method:

Whisk all these ingredients together. Let it rest in the fridge for about 5 minute before proceeding. 

To serve:

A handul of pistachios, crushed 

1 tsp of orange zest 

Method:

Top the grilled plums with the yogurt. Sprinkle the pistachios over this and then garnish with the orange zest. Serve immediately while the plums are still warm and the yogurt cold, it’s this contrast along with the array of textures and burst of flavours that makes this dish a winner. 

Tips:

You can grill the plums in the oven too. But it’s easier to control the heat on a pan so I’ve opted for this method. 

Instead of honey, you can use brown sugar for the plums and the yogurt too. If you’re feeling a bit indulgent then use cream cheese or mascarpone in place of the yogurt, the latter would be a better choice. 

In case you are allergic to nuts, then top with some roasted watermelon or pumpkin seeds. They’ll be just as delicious!]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Veggie Wednesdays On LocalBanya</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 9 Mar 2015 22:41:33 +0500</pubDate>
      <author>varsha.lokwane@ves.ac.in</author>
      <category>Offers</category>
      <description><![CDATA[Don’t get us wrong, we love our meats but not one meat can stand up on it’s own unless supported by plant products. Imagine no spices, no veggies and there goes all your salivating over your favourite dish.Which is why we love our veggies and know you love it too. So what better than having a day of the week dedicated to indulging in vegetable shopping? We thought so too! Presenting Veggie Wednesdays, when you can pick from a wide range of vegetables on our website. Starting today, you have a flat 15% off on select vegetables. And no, it is not one time! Watch out for discounts on vegetables every Wednesday!

So plan your weeks coz Banya now has three regulars on the offer aisle: Moustache Mondays, Funtastic Fridays and Veggie Wednesdays! Loot lo!]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Alphonso Is Back On LocalBanya!</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 9 Mar 2015 22:39:01 +0500</pubDate>
      <author>rucha.guntoorkar@ves.ac.in</author>
      <category>Offers</category>
      <description><![CDATA[India grows more mangoes than all of its other fruits combined.

Mango trees are long lived, with some trees over 300 years old still producing fruit.

The mango tree is a tropical Asian tree of the cashew family.

You thought we were just ranting? That’s a dose of mango trivia for you. But let’s put the trivia aside. Let’s sit down quietly for a while and truly accept the glorious truth that while the abomination that Mumbai summers are, is here, so is the only redeeming factor – mango. India takes its mangoes seriously. Mangos have been cultivated in India for about 5,000 years, and were originally not too big, fibrous fruits. There are now over 500 varieties grown there.

And this is Mumbai. This is mango capital. Mumbai waits with bated breath for two things: mangoes and monsoons. Our lives revolve around it and when the time really arrives, we can only think of aam panna, mangoes devoured whole, tucked away in rice containers to slowly ripen, the heady aroma of an aamras puri, of aamrakhand, of mango ice cream, barfis, of shipping away crates of the fruit to our less fortunate relatives in other cities with limited or rabidly expensive access to the king of all mangoes: the alphonso, better known as the haapus.

So when Banya gets you access to the first produce of the mango season, the gloriously intense, flavourful, Devgad Alphonso, it’s got to be because there’s unconditional love involved there somewhere.

Let’s not waste time with words. Let’s just sign in to our LocalBanya accounts and add dozens of this beautiful fruit to our cart. And let’s do so in a hurry because limited time offer! These mangoes are semi ripe – just store them in your rice container and they should be ready in 24-48 hours. How do you test if a mango is ready to be eaten? It should feel firm when you press the fruit gently but not too hard. The aroma should be heady, intense and full-bodied. It should not have greenish patches – if it does, it will take another day or two to be ready for you. Blackish-brown spots? It’s ageing, eat it before it goes bad!

Go ahead, keep calm & buy aam!]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five Simple Rules of Ayurveda for eating</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 9 Mar 2015 22:36:34 +0500</pubDate>
      <author>shariwa.malankar@ves.ac.in</author>
      <category>Food Tips</category>
      <description><![CDATA[No, we are not suddenly turning into nutrition experts on you folks! But we do carefully research what we tell you when it comes to eating healthy and wholesome. And Ayurveda, our very own homegrown science of well being and nutrition, has some universal rules when it comes to eating right, maintaining good health and leading a balanced life. So Banya looked into some of these rules and picked out the most essential ones that you ought to start practising right away!

1. Eat A Hearty Lunch: According to Ayurveda, your digestive powers rise and set with the sun. As the sun rises, your digestive system activates and it’s capacity to digest is at it’s peak by midday. This explains why lunch should be a hearty, fresh, warm and nourishing one.

2. Eat A Light Dinner: Post sunset, digestive powers are at their lowest and so, dinners ought to be light and nourishing, calming. A wholesome carb, such as whole wheat and a light protein such as fish or paneer is best suited for a night time meal. Also, Ayurveda suggests that because your digestion is very slow post sunset, dinner should be at least two hours before you hit the bed so you have had enough time to digest all that food and absorb it.

3. Drink Warm, Spice Infused Water: Warm water is believed to keep digestive tract clean and active. It also keeps your metabolism operating, ensuring a greater rate of nutrition absorption. Drinking lots of warm water also keeps you satiated so you do not crave for unhealthy between meals, which in turn helps you shed fat. You can consider infusing your warm water with ginger, lemon, cumin or cinnamon.

4. No Leftovers: Ayurveda believes that cooked food starts decomposing and breaking down very fast, despite refrigeration. The idea comes from the concept of prana or life force. Eating fresh ensures you get maximum prana from fruits and veggies. Keeping it for hours and days in the refrigerator may give you some rudimentary nutrition but it will not give you any vital energy. What’s worse, it may trigger hyperacidity from the chemical breakdown of ingredients in the cooked food.

5. Stay Active: Stay active. Move around. Walk, take the stairs, get up to change channels, opt for take out instead of home delivery, go to the store to buy instead of asking them to send over your requirements, keep getting up from your work station to refill your bottle of water. When you are active, your body’s metabolism kicks into action and keeps you fitter.

Sounds simple enough. Tell us if you are adopting any of these techniques and how they work out for you!]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Know Your Ingredient:Kokum</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 9 Mar 2015 22:34:24 +0500</pubDate>
      <author>sukhada.khatu@ves.ac.in</author>
      <category>Food Tips</category>
      <description><![CDATA[If you are Maharashtrian or Konkani, you are no stranger to the goodness and taste of Kokum. But we have been propagating eating healthy, local and fresh produce for ages now and thought that if you live in these regions, you must be eating regional too! Kokum is our Know Your Ingredient feature for the month and Banya thought you’d love to know more about this spice and incorporating it into your diet.

Origin: Kokum’s is a fruit of the Garcinia Indica plant and belongs to the mangosteen family. The plant and its fruit have culinary, industrial and pharmaceutical uses. It is indigenous to the western ghats of India so Kokum has been part of the Marathi and Konkani diets for a very long time. The fruit is potent enough to not require pesticides and fertilizers to thrive. It also does not demand irrigation. The fruit is dried in the sun to get what we know of as kokum or aamsul. It is a staple in cuisines across Maharashtra, Goa and also parts of Karnatak.

Alternate Uses: Kokum is also used in the manufacture of medicines, cosmetics and confectionary. And you may not believe it but grannies used to keep the extract of kokum, leftover from whatever was required for cooking, in houses infested with rats. Next morning, they’d find the rats lying around, high and woozy, and throw them out.

Medicinal Uses: Kokum is a coolant and can calm the most upset stomach. Acidity, bloating, gassy problems? Kokum does the trick. It also helps ease headaches from hangovers. An infusion made of kokum and garlic is also given to post natal mommies – it helps heal the uterus and restore your digestion. And the famous Kokum sharbat is used during summers to regulate body temperature on severely hot days and can heal a sunstroke. Remember that, summer is almost here! Kokum can also heal alleviate a heartburn, prevent cardiac arrests and has anti-cancerous health benefits.

Culinary Uses: Kokum is a perfect replacement to tamarind and has a similar sour profile. But it is definitely more astringent in flavour than tamarind is. Maharashtrian use it in a variety of curries and dal to introduce the sour taste, balancing it with chillies, garlic and spices. Perhaps the three most used dishes that celebrate the kokum are: aamti, kokum sherbet and solkadi. However, we are starting to see kokum in more modern avatars as well, sometimes in daiquiris, cocktails and even as salad dressings replacing citrus.

Storage: Kokum need not be refrigerated. It keeps well in a ceramic or steel air tight jar, stored in a cool, dark place. It keeps for a year.

You can buy your stash of kokum from the Banya aisles right now! Go ahead, make it a part of your cooking!]]></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>